嘿
Hey.
- 嘿   - 嘿
- Hey.     - Hey.
我想知道...
Listen, uh...
你们觉得我追得到吉宁吗？
You think I have a chance with Janine?
我们讨论过这件事了
Ugh, we've been through this.
对啊 别折磨自己了
Don't do this to yourself.
她已经明白表示不可能
She made it clear it isn't going to happen.
那我刚刚吻了她...
All right, then. I guess I shouldn't get too excited about the fact...
也不该太兴奋啰
that I just kissed her!
- 真的假的？ - 太好了
- Are you serious?     - That's great!
还得观察
Yeah, well, we'll see.
你吻了她？
You kissed her?
吻得可火热了
Oh, we kissed it up real nice.
你吻了她 然好呢？
So you kissed. Then what happened?
我就跑来告诉你们
I came over here to tell you guys.
而她在对面等你？
So she's waiting over there for you?
对
Yeah.
老友记 第六季 第十一集
（中央咖啡厅）
- 我得走了   - 好
- I gotta go.     - Okay.
我上舞蹈课要迟到了
I'm gonna be late for dance class.
好
Okay.
- 我真的已经迟到了   - 好
- Okay, now I'm really leaving.     - All right.
但你可以...
But can you just...
把嘴唇留下来吗？
just leave your lips?
- 再见   - 再见
- Bye.     - Bye.
你们吻过她吗？
Have you kissed her yet?
有够销魂的
It's awesome!
我怎么吻都吻不腻
I could do it forever.
她的吻功比我妈的厨艺还强
You know what? She kisses better than my mom cooks.
- 幸好你说的是厨艺   - 是吗
- I'm so glad you said "cooks."     - Right?
瑞秋 你得通知邮局你搬家了
Rachel, you've got to tell the post office that you've moved.
你的信件还是都寄到这里来
We still get your bills and stuff.
陶瓷货仓 剩下的可以扔了
Oh! Oh! Pottery Barn! You can throw the rest away.
我不是你的清洁工
I'm not your garbage man.
我是你的邮差
I'm your mailman.
摩妮卡 你看
Monica, look.
这里有我订的桌子
Here is that table that I ordered. Ah!
- 你是在陶瓷货仓买的？ - 对 这叫药师桌
- You got it from Pottery Barn?     - Yeah. It's an apothecary table.
有谁知道药师是什么吗？
Does anyone even know what an apothecary is?
就是药剂师
A pharmacist.
瑞秋 菲比最讨厌陶瓷货仓了
Phoebe hates Pottery Barn.
我也讨厌陶瓷货仓
I hate Pottery Barn too.
我才在床上坐坐 就被赶出去
They kicked me out just because I sat on a bed.
你脱了裤子钻进被子里
You took off your pants and got under the sheets.
我很睏
I was tired.
菲比讨厌陶瓷货仓？
Phoebe hates Pottery Barn?
量产的东西她都讨厌
She hates mass-produced stuff.
她觉得她的家俱 应该要有历史 有典故
She thinks her furniture should have a story behind it.
这有典故啊
This has a story behind it.
这是大老远从白原店运来的
They had to ship it all the way from the White Plains store.
她喜欢独一无二
It's got to be one-of-a-kind.
就像她那个丑到爆的水果陶碗
Like that God-awful ceramic fruit bowl she has on her counter?
那是我做的
Hey! I made that for her.
- 你会捏陶？ - 对
- You made pottery?     - Yeah.
是从垃圾堆捡来的啦
I made it out of a fruit bowl I found in the garbage.
你把桌子搬回家 肯定会被念到死
If you put that in her apartment, you'll never hear the end of it.
好 我就说那是古董
I'll tell her that it's an antique.
她不必知道它的出处
She doesn't have to know where it came from.
你看这些小抽屉
Ah, I love these little drawers.
上面说可以放三百张CD
Oh, look! It says that it holds 300 CDs.
正如往昔的药师桌
Ah, just like the apothecary tables of yore.
然后农夫说
So the farmer says:
“那不是母牛 你也不是在挤奶”
"That's not a cow, and you're not milking."
你们能在一起真好
I'm so glad you're together.
钱德跟我一直在一对情侣朋友 现在总算找到了
We wanted a couple to go out with and now we have one.
我们是成双又成对
We're a couple of couples.
今晚真开心 那家餐厅好棒
I had so much fun tonight. What a great restaurant!
钱德 我居然让你请客
And Chandler, I can't believe I let you pay for this one.
再次感谢
Thanks again, man.
明天要不要过来？我来做我说的那种意大利面
If you come over tomorrow, I'll make pasta.
- 那太好了   - 好的
- That'd be great!     - Okay.
不过至少让我们带酒来
But at least let us bring the wine.
- 不必客气了   - 不行 我坚持
- You don't have to.     - Ah, I insist.
- 你会买吧？ - 会啦
- You'll get the wine, right?     - Yeah.
- 那就晚安   - 明天见
- Okay, good night.     - See you tomorrow.
好期待喔
Can't wait.
我们要怎么逃过一劫？
How are we going to get out of that one?
- 什么？ - 我没办法连续应酬他们...
- What?     - I can't handle two nights in a row...
两晚
with them.
摩妮卡和钱德有什么不好？
What's wrong with them?
不晓得 他们就是有点...
They're just a little...
哈啦
blah!
哈啦？
Blah?
他很哈啦 她...
Well, you know, he's blah. She's just...
她很娇小嗓门却很大
She's very loud for such a small person.
他们是我最要好的朋友
Uh, they're my best friends.
我们不能跟他们往来吗？ 那可就麻烦了
Are you saying we can't go out? 'Cause that'd be a problem.
不是 往来当然可以
Of course we can still hang out with them.
只是不要连续两晚
Just not two nights in a row.
- 好吗？ - 好吧
- Okay?     - I guess.
谢谢
Thank you.
要我卖了朋友 给你买礼物都行
I'll sell my friends and use the money to buy you presents.
- 嘿   - 嘿
- Hey.     - Hey.
好棒的桌子 在哪里买的？
Ooh! What a great table! Where did you get it?
你猜
Guess.
跳蚤市场？
Um, a flea market?
我就知道你会一猜就中
Ha, I knew you would get it on the first guess.
很酷吧 这是药师桌
Isn't it cool? It's an apothecary table.
哦 哇
Ah, wow.
你可以想像 他们就是把药材...
You can just imagine that this is where...
存放在这里面
they kept all their stuff to make potions.
- 你知道？ - 对啊
- You know?     - Ooh, yes.
几乎能闻到鸦片的味道
Ooh, you can almost smell the opium.
就是啊
Almost.
多少钱？
Oh, how much was it?
才5百
Just only 500 bucks.
跳蚤市场买的要5百？
500 bucks at a flea market?
我以为你是问...
I thought you meant how much was it...
当年全新时的价钱
when it was new, back then.
- 不是   - 就是说嘛
- Oh, no.     - Yeah, no.
因为是跳蚤市场 所以差不多1块钱
It was at a flea market, so it was like a dollar.
- 1块钱？ - 再加50元
- A dollar?     - And fifty?
总共51元
So it was like one and fifty dollars.
- 他们用古法算钱   - 对
- They gave you the old-time pricing.     - Yeah.
这是哪个年代的？
Well, what period is it from?
往昔年代
Uh, it's from yore.
就是往昔的时代
Like, the "days of yore," you know?
我知道
Yes. Yes, I do.
- 天哪 真是太完美   - 确实不错
- It's just perfect.     - Oh, good.
这一定有很棒的典故
I bet it has a great story too.
卖方有提到它的出处或...
Did they tell you where it's from or...
有 这个我知道 它来自白原
Yes, that I know. This is from, uh, White Plains.
- 白原   - 嗯哼
- White Plains.     - Mm-hm.
听起来好神奇
Ooh, it sounds like such a magical place.
- 我们来了   - 嗨
- I'm here.     - Hi!
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
- 你喜欢吗？ - 完了
- You like it?     - Oh, my God!
这是我的新药师桌
It's my new apothecary table!
罗斯 菲比就快到了 不能让她看到
Phoebe'll be here any second. She can't see this.
为什么？她一定会喜欢 这是好东西
Why not? She'll love it. It's the real thing.
是在陶瓷货仓买的
I got it at Pottery Barn.
我知道 我也买了一张
I know. I bought the same one.
她看到你的桌子 就会知道我骗她
And if she sees your table, she'll know I lied.
- 我说我们的是原版   - 为什么？
- I said ours was an original.     - Why?
因为她讨厌陶瓷货仓
Because she hates Pottery Barn.
她讨厌陶瓷货仓？
She hates Pottery Barn?
我也很惊讶 她说那是量产
She says it's all mass-produced...
没有真品 大家买的都一样
nothing is authentic, and everyone winds up having the same stuff.
她随时会进来 拿个东西盖住它好吗？
So come on! Can we cover this up, please?
不要
What? No, no.
我才不要遮遮掩掩的
I am not gonna hide it from Phoebe.
不过我也买了很漂亮的床单
Although I did get some great Pottery Barn sheets.
我忘了他们也有出床单
Ooh, I forgot they made sheets!
废话
Heh, yeah.
她居然会讨厌陶瓷货仓
I still can't believe she hates Pottery Barn.
别再念了 她又不是讨厌你
It's not like she hates you.
但是陶瓷货仓耶
Yeah, but Pottery Barn?
我觉得根本是她怪胎
You know what I think? She's just weird.
因为她是双胞胎 双胞胎都很怪
It's because she's a twin. Twins are weird.
她不是怪 她只是希望她的东西独一无二
She's not weird. She likes her stuff to be one-of-a-kind.
什么最不独一无二？双胞胎
Huh. You know what's not one-of-a-kind? A twin!
菲比来了 把灯关掉看电影吧
Let's turn out the lights and watch the movie.
- 好...好漂亮的床单   - 喜欢是吧？
- Hey, ooh, cool sheet!     - You like it?
- 想知道哪里买的吗？ - 好啊
- You want to know where I got it?     - Sure.
他是在跳蚤市场买的
At a flea market.
你上跳蚤市场买床单？
You buy your sheets at a flea market?
罗斯 别这么小气吧
Come on, you gotta loosen the purse strings a little.
- 嘿   - 嘿
- Hey.     - Hey.
晚餐再过20分钟就好了 好兴奋喔
Dinner will be ready in 20 minutes.
这是你今晚要带过来的酒
Here is the wine to bring over tonight.
你想送花给摩妮卡...
You were also gonna buy Monica flowers...
却买不起 因为你付了昨晚晚餐的钱
but you couldn't because you paid for dinner last night.
谢谢 但今晚只有我要过去
Thanks. But, uh, it's just gonna be me tonight.
- 吉宁怎么了？ - 她病得很重
- What happened to Janine?     - She's, uh, really sick.
- 真糟糕   - 对啊 她整天都在房里
- That's too bad.     - Yeah, she's been in there all day.
发高烧 鼻塞...
Uh, high fever, nose problem. It's...
痰痰痰痰痰
phlegm, phlegm, phlegm, phlegm, phlegm.
摩妮卡 钱德
Monica! Chandler!
今晚真抱歉 乔伊说了吗？
I'm sorry about tonight. I don't know if Joey told you...
有出戏我一定得去看 抱歉
but I couldn't get out of going to this play.
玩得开心点 好
Have a great time, huh?
怪了 没有痰啊
That's funny, I saw no phlegm.
不 她真的病得很重
Oh, no, she really is sick.
那她为什么要去看戏？
Then why is she going to a play?
你知道的 感冒想退烧...
Uh, well, you know, "Starve a fever...
就要去看戏
go to a play for a cold."
乔伊 吉宁为什么不来吃饭？
Why is Janine not coming over for dinner?
她不想连续两晚都陪你们
Uh, she didn't want to hang out with you guys two nights in a row.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
她为什么不想陪我们？
Why doesn't she want to hang out with us?
因为她觉得你很哈啦
Because she, uh, thinks that you are "blah."
而摩妮卡 你的嗓门太大
And that, uh, you, Monica, are too loud.
什么？
What?!
What?
所以她昨晚只是假装开心？
So she just pretended to have a good time?
她当面骗我们？
She was lying to our faces?
太扯了
I can't believe this.
她凭什么批评我们？
Who is she to judge us?
- 我们对她多好   - 我才不是哈啦 我是谈笑风生
- We couldn't have been nicer to her.     - And I am not "blah." I am a hoot!
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
拜托啦 别生气
Come on, please, you guys. Don't be mad.
她一定是...
I'm sure she said it...
紧张才会这么说 你们是我最要好的朋友
because she was nervous 'cause you're my best friends.
我们又是第一次约会
And it was our first date.
而且她病得很重
Plus, she's really sick.
你明明说那是假的
You said you made that up!
但你不觉得生病比看戏好吗？
But isn't the "sick" thing better than the "play" thing?
都很好 我通常都说摩妮卡又醉了
They're both good. I generally just go with, "Monica's drunk again."
拜托啦 再给她一次机会
Come on, please just give her another chance.
- 她定会喜欢你们的   - 当然好
- She'll come around, I promise.     - Of course we will.
- 回去煮饭吧   - 好
- Come on, we gotta make dinner.     - Okay.
我不喜欢那个女人
I do not like that woman!
我听得见
I can hear you!
我的嗓门真的很大
I am loud!
哦
Aw.
真好笑
Isn't it good?
菲比 别把脚翘在我的新...
Can you please not put your feet up on my new...
旧床单上
old sheet.
好
Oh, sure.
我的药师桌
My apothecary table!
- 什么？ - 不
- What?     - No!
- 这张桌子是哪里买的？ - 陶瓷货仓 好吗？
- Where did you get this?     - At Pottery Barn, okay?
天哪 菲比
Oh, my God!
陶瓷货仓抄袭我们古董的设计
Pottery Barn has ripped off the design of our antique!
天哪 要是他们会抄袭
Wow. If they've ripped off our table...
那张桌子一定不只值51元
ours must be worth much more than one and fifty dollars.
这张连鸦片的味道都没有
This doesn't even smell like opium.
当然没有 只有你洒出来的酒味
It smells like wine, which you spilled.
谢谢你还毁了我的床单
And thanks for wrecking my sheet.
别激动 罗斯 我赔你80分就是了
Ross, calm down. I'll give you the 80 cents.
再来一次
Okay, one more time.
钱德 你还要柳橙汁吗？
Would you like some orange juice?
- 音量刚刚好   - 就是啊
- Perfect decibel.     - I know!
嘿 嘿
Hey.
你们在干什么？
Uh, what are you guys doing?
没什么 就是聊天哈啦
Nothing. We're just talking. You know, blah-blah-blah.
别这样 你们说过要尽力的
Come on, you said you were gonna try.
我来找你们一起去看电影
I came over to invite you to a movie with me and Janine.
- 你们觉得呢？ - 非常乐意
- What do you say?     - I'd like to...
但是...
but I'm not sure if we have the time.
真好笑...我也很无奈
Ha, very funny. I don't know what to do.
我真的很希望你们处得来
I really want you to get along.
拜托你们跟我们去吧 这是你们欠我的
Please, come to the movie with us. You owe me.
- 我们欠你？ - 没错
- We owe you?     - That's right.
你们刚交往时 我帮了很多忙
I helped you out in the start of your relationship.
我帮你们偷鸡模狗6个月
I helped you sneak around for six months.
跟白痴一样
I looked like an idiot.
还被羞辱
And I was humiliated.
却只赚了2百
And I only made $200.
我们没有给你钱
We didn't give you any money.
你以为我不知道吗？
You don't think I know that?
我不知道该拿它配藤条餐桌椅...
I can't decide if it goes better by the new chair...
黄色书桌...
the Sahara desk...
还是螺形托脚桌
or the Parker console table.
原来你们这里也有陶瓷货仓
I didn't know there was a Pottery Barn up here.
- 我知道 我有点买疯了   - 有点？
- I know, I went a little crazy.     - A little?
这里就像目录第72页
Your place looks like page 72 of the catalog.
看
Look at that!
- 装饰鸟笼 大号的   - 嘿 嘿
- The ornamental birdcage! Large.     - Ha, ha.
罗斯 小心 那个很老了
Oh, Ross? Be careful. That is very old.
殖民地时代早期的鸟商 都用那个带鸟上市场
Colonial bird merchants used to bring their birds to market in that.
有意思
Fascinating.
又一个惊人的发现
Another amazing find! Wow.
- 它定也有很棒的典故   - 没错
- I bet this has a great story too.     - It does.
这是殖民地时期 分隔房间的装置
It is a room-separating apparatus from Colonial times.
有好多东西都来自殖民地时期
Huh, a lot of this stuff is from the Colonial times.
还有哪些时期呢 瑞秋？
What are some other time periods, Rachel?
有往昔
Well, there's yore.
还有昨年
Ahem, and, uh, you know, yesteryear.
瑞秋对这种东西真的很有眼光
Rachel has such a good eye for this stuff.
罗斯 如果你家要重新布置...
Ross, if you ever decide to redecorate...
我觉得很有必要重新布置
and I think you should...
你应该找瑞秋帮忙
you should ask Rachel to help.
他才不需要我的帮忙
Aw, he doesn't need my help.
拜托 他早该扔掉那些... 你是怎么说的？
I think he's ready to get rid of the... What'd you call it?
廉价的赝品和恐龙垃圾
The, uh, "cheap knockoffs and dinosaur junk"?
是吗？
Really?
你知道吗？ 既然你这么清楚我的需求
You know, since you have such a great sense of what I need...
我这里有60元
Uh, here's 60 bucks.
你带着菲比去殖民时期跳蚤市场
Why don't you take Phoebe down to that Colonial, uh, flea market...
帮我办货吧
and get me some stuff?
我觉得菲比不会想去
I don't think Phoebe wants to come.
- 不 我想去   - 她想去
- I do want to.     - She does want to.
- 她想去   - 没错
- She does want to.     - Yeah!
我不知道该说什么 上次比较有得进
I guess the flea market was just better last time.
至少我帮罗斯买了床单 没错
Well, at least I got these sheets for Ross.
看 是陶瓷货仓
Ugh, look at this. Pottery Barn.
别看了
Ugh, yeah, you know what? Don't look at it.
- 真的 别看了   - 你看
- Seriously, don't look at it.     - Look!
他们抄袭我们的咖啡桌
There's the table they stole from us.
那些混蛋我们走
Oh, those bastards! Let's go.
那台电风扇跟我们的有点像 还有那个鸟笼和...
That fan kind of looks like ours, and the birdcage, and...
等一下 这根本就是我们的客厅
Wait a second, this is our exact living room!
才不是呢
No, it's not.
我们的完全不一样
Come on, ours is totally different.
我们没有... 我们没有那盏灯
I mean, we don't have the... We don't have that lamp.
还有那扇屏风是在另一边
And that screen is on the other side.
天哪 那些都是陶瓷货仓的东西
Oh, my God. This is where you got all our stuff.
- 陶瓷货仓的东西 我的天哪   - 不是
- Pottery Barn! Oh, my God!     - No. No.
好啦 你说对了 对不起
Okay, I did, all right? I'm sorry.
菲彼 我想要这些东西 又知道你讨厌陶瓷货仓
I wanted this stuff and I know how you feel about Pottery Barn.
- 你不要生气   - 但是我气死了
- Come on, don't be mad.     - No, but I am mad.
这代表世间所有丑恶的东西...
Because this stuff is what's wrong with the world...
都在我的客厅里
and it's in my living room...
而我却只想着我没有那盏灯
and all I can think about is how I don't have that lamp!
那就买下那盏灯
Well, then, honey, buy the lamp.
我们有罗斯给的60元
We have that 60 bucks from Ross.
不行 不行
I can't! I can't!
除非...
Unless...
你是说我不买那盏灯 你就要搬走吗？
Are you saying you'd move out if I didn't buy that lamp?
不 我不会搬走
No, I'm not gonna move out!
你是说我不买那盏灯 你就要搬走吗？
But are you saying that you would move out if I didn't buy that lamp?
- 没错 我定会搬走   - 那我就没办法了
- Yes! I would so move out.     - Then I don't have a choice.
- 那我就得买那盏灯   - 没错
- I have to buy that lamp!     - That's right.
不过至少那张药师桌是真货
But at least the apothecary table's real.
真好 大家都很尽兴吧？
This was great. Didn't everybody have a great time?
我很尽兴 真的
I did. I really did. And I've got to say...
还有很抱歉上次聚会后 我态度怪怪的
I'm sorry if I was weird after the last time we went out.
可能是紧张吧
I guess I was just nervous.
- 我们完全可以理解   - 别放在心上
- That's understandable.     - Don't worry about it.
那么我们可以再一起出去罗？
So we can go out again?
- 当然可以   - 当然
- Absolutely.     - Well, good.
- 那就 晚安   - 晚安
- Okay, well, good night.     - Good night.
看吧？
See, huh?
很好玩吧？
Wasn't that fun?
我们非搬家不可
We have got to move.
什么？
What?
我就知道
I knew it!
你的嗓门也不小 死丫头
You're not so quiet yourself, missy!
我哈啦？ 比看现代舞更无聊的...
I'm blah? The only thing more boring than modern dance...
就是听你聊现代舞
is you talking about it.
钱德...
Oh, Chandler...
我刚才看得浑然忘我
I just lost myself in the movement."
我知道你在说话
You know, I know you're talking...
但我只听到叽哩呱啦叽哩呱啦
but all I hear is blah-blah-blah-blah-blah.
我们现在就出去 马上
All right, you and me! Let's go, right now!
好了 够了够了
All right, enough!
你们回去我要跟吉宁谈一谈
Enough! You two, go home. I gotta talk to Janine.
你绝对可以打倒她
I really think you could take her.
别让我在走廊上碰到你
You better hope I don't see you in the hallway!
好了...
All right. Uh...
我们有个小小的问题
Look, we got a little bit of a problem here.
他们是我的朋友 你不能对他们无礼
You can't my treat my friends that way.
- 他们也对我出言不逊 我知道   - 我会找他们谈
- They said stuff to me too.     - I know, I'll talk to them about it.
他们对我很重要
They mean so much to me.
就像我的家人
They're like my family, you know?
如果你们一见面就吵 我...
If you guys are gonna be fighting all the time...
我们就不能在一起 这是行不通的
I don't think we can be together. It just can't work, okay?
行不通的
It can't.
我很不开心
I'm very upset.
好吧
Okay.
要是我过去道歉呢？
Would it help if I apologized?
好啊
Yeah.
那就太好了
That'd be very helpful.
我说过在走廊上碰到会怎样？
What did I tell you about the hall?
我只是要过去向你们道歉
I was coming over to apologize for my behavior.
我很希望能跟你们做朋友
I'd really like it if we could be friends.
我知道那样会让乔伊很高兴...
Well, I know that would make Joey happy, so...
所以我也愿意
I would like that too.
- 太好了   - 来吧
- Great.     - Now, come on.
- 很高兴能达成共识   - 我也是
- I'm glad we worked it out.     - Me too.
- 回头见   - 再见
- I'll see you.     - Bye.
- 听都听得见   - 够了 来吧
- Or I'll hear you.     - That's it, big girl!
慢着
Wait!
你最好快逃
You'd better run!
你听见了吗？ 听见了
Did you hear that?
- 我该怎么办？ - 难为你了
- What am I gonna do?     - I'm sorry, man.
- 要去看吗？ - 当然
- Want to go watch?     - Yeah!
- 嘿   - 嘿
- Hey.     - Hey.
- 大家好   - 她搬出去了吗？
- How you doing?     - So, uh, did she move out?
差不多了
Pretty much.
你居然就这样跟她分手
I can't believe you just broke up with her.
不适合就是不适合
When it's not right, you know it.
- 你还好吧？ - 死不了
- You okay?     - I'll be all right.
- 我有办法让你开心   - 什么办法？
- You know what'd cheer you up?     - What?
我明晚要教侵蚀理论
I'm giving this lecture on erosion theories tomorrow night.
你应该来听
I think you should come.
我确实开心多了
You're right, that did cheer me up.